you take them now you optimize them now
for what it's going to do for you 303
years from now not the way it makes you
feel now do not get caught up into only
the feel-good effects I'm not going to
take it if I don't feel it understand
that what you do now will have a
profound effect on you 30 years from now
if you will do it daily for the next 30
Years pregnant alone now I'll use it and
older men and you know to improve memory
and help in neuronal repair and of
course you use it as you as you stayed
in these younger men that have had brain
injuries so tell us your feelings on
pregnant on itself it's to to me you
know if people if people are like I
don't want to take any hormones I don't
want to take any hormones I just want to
do my testosterone or I just you know I
don't have Financial I'm not financially
able to do them all and they say which
ones can I cut out first I will
typically say well if you're going to
cut out any hormone and not take it at
all I guess it would be pregnant alone
on my list but I'd recommend that you
take them all because we've already
talked about it working synergistically
with all your hormone other hormon but
if Dave and I had to really throw it out
there the the the the data in humans and
randomized control trials is somewhat
Limited in pregnant alone compared to
the others although there's plenty of
studies out there which which I have
it's just not as robust as our other
studies but I do use it to improve
memory and help a neuronal repair how
about you yeah completely and and it's
kind of like when people ask that
question of like oh if you could only do
10 exercises for the rest of your life
what would they be and I'd say why can I
only do 10 if they say oh if if I could
only take three hormones what would it
be it's like why can't you take five
like they're not it's not and especially
like I don't know about you but I get
them comp I get like a a a morning
capsule and a night capsule so I
compound them together so that way you
know we can do do whatever we can to
make it easier and more economical for
people but yeah I mean I I guess if
people if if I had an older gentleman
who was like what's what's one hormone I
could cut out if for some reason I
couldn't I mean yeah I i' probably
pregnant alone if if I had to but I
wouldn't um but but yeah so when it
comes to pregnanolone pregnanolone
exerts a lot of its effects in the body
via conversion to Progesterone and Alo
pregnanolone and these are where it has
its calming effect so it's a what's
called a Gaba uh Gabba a receptor
positive aleric modulator which which is
a fancy term for making the Garba a
receptor more sensitive which is the
same mechanism of action as benzoin
Valium XX ET so when someone is
deficient in pregnanolone what what
pregnanolone also does in the brain is
it is very neuroprotective so anytime
someone takes anything that's
intoxicating whether it's caffeine or
amphetamine or alcohol or whatever it is
the brain increases pregnanolone release
to basically prevent your brain from
getting too overe excited and going into
an oxidative stress state so it's like a
thermostat and it it seems to have as
well as DHEA have a lot of these
thermostat properties throughout the
body it works on the endoc canabo system
so a lot of these benefits that we see
from Cannabis are happening on the CB1
and CB2 receptors which pregnanolone
also buy with it's technically aoid so
it's like it's like it's it's got like
your your own endogenous version of of
CBD almost as well that's why you see
being used in lot of these substant
abuse disorders in the state absolutely
they de on and I I often find that
people who are pregnant alone deficient
will self-medicate with CBD because it
works on a lot of the same Pathways So
Pregnant alone is is very much I like to
call it the breakes I I do find that
when people are deficient in
pregnanolone when you combine
pregnanolone and melatonin they sleep
like a baby um it it's it it seems to
massively reduce the Baseline level of
stress in the body and sometimes this
stress can be perceived mentally as
anxiety if you're constantly mentally
feeling like there's something wrong
maybe there is and maybe it's inside and
maybe you're reacting to that it's like
a crying baby it's saying problem
problem problem you don't know what it
is so when I see younger guys who've got
brain injuries when they've got pregnant
alone deficiencies the main thing that
you see Pop Up is anxiety and insomnia
and being what I call Wired and tired
it's like being full of beans in a bad
way like having it's the bad part of
having too much caffeine and the thing
that I see like when I when I referen
this gentleman who I spoke about the
other day who I referred to yourself is
that he had all these symptoms of you
know low testosterone which is low
hormones at the age of 60 and the the
main thing that didn't improve was the
brain fog and the ability to articulate
the ability to actually get the words
out that you're wanting to articulate
and and and I always stutter on this
point ironically but it's when you're
actually trying to articulate what's on
your mind and when you're able to speak
with good fluidity and speak well and
confidently and you know not stammer
over your words or or or lose your
tongue and I think pregalin makes your
brain work better it it's it's a very
powerful neurosteroid and it's very
protective against cognitive decline and
it's also like as you mentioned before
insulin resistance is when I said those
four diseases of Aging they're all
insulin resistance Foundation absolutely
and dementia is type three diabetes so I
think that when I look mechanistically
PR and DHEA are very important for
energy metabolism in the brain which you
can cognitively feel but it's also going
to be the thing that's going to protect
you when you get older and that's what I
think is very important is people want
to get to 70 80 years old everyone's
talking about longevity it's like but
you want to actually be doing well when
you get there you don't want to spend
the last 20 years of your life you know
not being able to clean up after
yourself you want to actually be sharp
and present and functional and that's
what pregnenolone DHEA especially
together are going to be able to
facilitate for you it's just pregalin
into the brakes and and DHEA is more
like the accelerator everyone please
listen to what Dave's saying I wish they
could make a reel on what he just said
which they will I'm sure in that look
you take them now you optimize them now
for what it's going to do for you 303
years from now not the way it makes you
feel now do not get caught up into only
the feel-good effects I'm not going to
take it if I don't feel it understand
that what you do now will have a
profound effect on you 30 years from now
if you will do it daily for the next 30
Years it is it it's so hard to get
people to to understand that and do it
they they'll start for a while and then
people get complacent and they just stop
and once again they'll just start start
looking for an easy button somewhere but
there is not one there is not one but
for me and you taking hormones just so
easy it's as easy as brushing our teeth
you know just it's just as easy so so
please it is about prevention and do not
wait until you get symptoms of
deficiency do not wait until you get a
disease or disorder to start treating it
because that's how we're trained in
medicine we're trained to treat you once
you get the disease you're trained to go
to the doctor once you get sick of the
disease we're trying to prevent you
getting that age related disease we're
trying to prevent insulin resistance
trying to reverse insulin resistance so
please listen to everything that Dave
just
said
[Music]